Ashwin Chalaka

408-834-3724 | San Francisco Bay Area ashwin.chalaka@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/ashwinchalaka

GitHub

github.com/ashwinchalaka

Full-stack web/mobile developer and software engineer with 1+ years of experience. Proficient in numerous programming languages, modern frameworks, and development tools. Quickly learns new technologies. Schooled in clean object-oriented design and easy-to-follow documentation. Most notably accomplished an enterprise web solution within 4 months as a technical and organizational lead.

Education

San Jose State University

B.S. Software Engineering (3rd year / Junior)

Foothill-De Anza College

Computer Science for transfer (2017 - 2020), GPA: 3.66

Oregon State University

Industrial Engineering (2014 - 2017)

	<u>Projects</u>	
Visual	Coach	Notes API
Creates visualization for CSV dataset.	Technology aid for skill building.	Convert anything to notes.
 Java, JavaScript SpringJS MongoDB HTML5, CSS3 	 JavaScript AngularJS NodeJS, ExpressJS MongoDB HTML5, CSS3 	 Swift (for iOS), Python Django HTML5, CSS3 API's: #1, #2, etc.

Experience

STEM-Away.Inc, Santa Clara, CA and remote-work - Full Stack Developer and Project Lead

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

- Controlled the product development life cycle of the STEM-Away *Career Statistic Tool* and successfully launched within 4 months
- Resolved a process bottleneck that immediately advanced the team from project planning to the prototyping stage
- Engineered ...
 - a Python-Django MVC architecture and deployed to Google Cloud that brought the project to life
 - a script to process API data through validation and filtration into a PostgreSQL database which eliminated need to manually verify the data
 - an admin tool inside of the Python-Django application to securely edit previous entries into the database

Coding Dojo, San Jose, CA - Web & Mobile Developer Accelerator Student

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018

• Exceeded 1,000 hours of onsite training in web/mobile development earning job-ready proficiency in 3 full-stack technologies and a double black-belt certification

Technical Skills

- Formal Classes

- Computer Science:
 - Object Oriented Design, Assembly Language, Data structures, Algorithms, Discrete Math, Calculus, Physics
- Software development:
 - Java

- Coding Dojo, On the Job, and Self Taught

- Web development:
 - MEAN Stack, Python, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, MVC, AWS EC2 Deployment, Google Cloud, Modularization
- Frontend:
 - AngularJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, The Box Model, AJAX, Adobe Photoshop, GIMP
- Backend:
 - Django, NodeJs, Express, Flask, Session, Bcrypt,
- Database:
 - SQL, noSQL, mySQL, SQLite, ORMs, MongoDB, Mongoose, Models, Relational Tables
- Mobile development:
 - Swift (iOS), Auto Layout, CoreData, CoreMotion, CoreLocation, MapKit, UIKit,
 AVFoundation
- API:
 - JSON, RESTful, Postman
- Developer tools:
 - GitHub, Microsoft VS Code, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Sublime Text, Asana, Slack

Organizational Leadership

- In School

- Worked as a notetaker and tutor for registered disabled, disadvantaged, and struggling students, see <u>LinkedIn</u> for full list of prior jobs
- STEM-Away see endorsement here
 - Detailed project organization and communication of technical information, as seen here
 - Partnered with supervisor to build a full team and personally trained entry-level members
 - Coordinated remote and in-person meetings between mentees and mentors and delegated tasks to all team members